Hello, welcome to the next episode of German in Hindi.
Today
we are going to learn an important but
very easy concept in this, that is
in these different Puranas, so this name
sounds a bit hard, so let's directly go into it,
which three are
we going to learn, man, this mand construction is very
simple, we will start learning one by one, so
first of all see, man, right now, let's
not spare you, till now we have
seen MLA double n Udayan, meaning man,
this is a bit different, this is main and its
meaning is like one in English,
its Hindi meaning is not directly, that
means it is difficult to translate it directly, you
can say that a man or a human being should do this, for example, it happened, one
must learn German, one must learn
German, it means what someone means, German is
smooth, it is a good thing, its meaning is, so you
can do it in technical Hindi, which brother, a
man should learn German, I could not understand,
third person singular, it is third person,
but I don't know who it is, but what is its basic meaning  That is
German okay it is a good thing one must not have got it one should not
lie
who should not tell it to anyone are you understanding the
basic concept if your
English why and
this product Chakli mine consisting of German let's try a little
test then it will become a little easy okay so first of all you must
learn German one must learn German so what will happen mango
musaddi red chilli leban very simply
slide plane like I have given
this page similarly one must be
polite means a man should
point then what will happen human
police celery or a man should not lie
means yes this one should not one should not alive so
what will happen man joint
evil fruits a shrink hard sentence let's try
one needs modification in one wants to learn
German one wonders notification even wants to learn German so
what will happen look man
browser man proud feel good old when
uddhav children will fill the mango feel good old when
our oil day they will and simple right now
see there is one small thing that as
we said one must  Learn German, you
can say Germany, almost similar
meaning Darwin Easy brand beer mission
launched in Lebanon, look at the answer, you say one is
cool, so one level is Amolak, Sudhar, heavenly
affair level, that's why if you use one, it will
look like this, click here, it is
towards the level, similarly, Maan means one, similarly,
Lemon, Maal means relation, Manav means someone, let's
see how to use it, then
you will immediately understand that brother, all one
must help, help someone who should do something,
sum1 must help, so what will happen,
this mind, mark helper, again,
third person singular, what is the only thing, this
mand judge, all that
is in nominative, so this maal, when it is positive,
it will be mountain and for dot euro, it will be
mar dem, like
medium and heat medium happened, similarly you will have someone
today, that's why we also learned a little late,
this mileage, this mandal, this momentum, so now we must meet someone, a
game officer, this monetary fund
and his mind, dandruff, because the
subject of this is  Relationship is an object and similarly
they must play with someone they must play with
someone what happens don't you so what will happen is
this madam gave and misson minute this respect
dums clan is simple ride and similarly the
opposite of respect is non non neman neman neman
use someone you see no one
helped the route that no big a
help us so what will happen neem mand khattar
margi whole fun no one helped the brain the
foundation work is on so
what will happen from that that is why mar
gloves morgan mar close both hands
this mark playlist fuel total because
march is the subject neem object ok similarly
marketplace with 90 mark victim minute
ni visit why because the digestive system
is simple what you have to remember is that you have to
use mother this is to use and
use construction now see all those
different persons for 3 small one and a quarter inch
that you see this you know so I am
giving you the
article of means something means something means nothing nothing  Meaning everything, if we
see small examples of this then you will come to
know about it, so what will happen first is
advance in hands and I heard that you have eaten something,
height 21 years, pointing towards Vansh, Gail
and I want nothing, time advance list, by the way, I have to do all this,
I was doing everything alone,
what will happen in
this musalle deadline, butter cave, like
butter network, means some tips, means nothing less, means
everything, simple as that, what was important is
that mother's is a little different from the use of mother
and whether to use it or not,
sometimes you use it completely and there is no
need not to use that, the important thing is
that how do you use demand in third person singular in India,
I hope you have understood some concept,
we will meet in the next episode
two